<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Posts on The Weekly Arxiv</title><link>https://weeklyarxiv.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on The Weekly Arxiv</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.134.3</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 13:28:15 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://weeklyarxiv.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>100 Years of (eXplainable) AI: Reflecting on Advances and Challenges in Deep Learning and Explainability</title><link>https://weeklyarxiv.github.io/posts/2024/12/100-years-of-explainable-ai/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 13:28:15 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://weeklyarxiv.github.io/posts/2024/12/100-years-of-explainable-ai/</guid><description>&lt;p>As we navigate the complexities of the ever-evolving era of Large Language Models (LLMs) and AI governance, it&amp;rsquo;s essential to take a step back and reflect on the remarkable journey of Artificial Intelligence (AI) over the past century. The concept of Explainable AI (XAI) has been a recurring theme throughout this journey, with a growing emphasis on developing AI systems that can provide insights into their decision-making processes. In this blog post, we&amp;rsquo;ll delve into the history of XAI, highlighting key milestones, advances, and challenges in deep learning and explainability, and explore the current state of AI governance.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>20 GitHub Repositories That Will Supercharge Your Coding Journey</title><link>https://weeklyarxiv.github.io/posts/2024/12/mindblowing-github-repositories-you-never-knew-existed/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 13:02:18 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://weeklyarxiv.github.io/posts/2024/12/mindblowing-github-repositories-you-never-knew-existed/</guid><description>&lt;p>The world of software development is constantly evolving, with new tools, frameworks, and libraries emerging every day. GitHub, the leading platform for code collaboration, serves as a treasure trove of these innovations, hosting millions of open-source projects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While some repositories are widely known, many hidden gems remain undiscovered. These repositories offer unique insights, practical solutions, and valuable resources that can significantly enhance your coding journey.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This blog post explores 20 exceptional GitHub repositories that deserve a place on every developer&amp;rsquo;s radar.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Jailbreaking the Highway: The Vulnerabilities of Digital License Plates</title><link>https://weeklyarxiv.github.io/posts/2024/12/digital-license-plate-jailbreak-hack/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 18:33:10 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://weeklyarxiv.github.io/posts/2024/12/digital-license-plate-jailbreak-hack/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="the-dark-side-of-digital-license-plates-a-threat-to-road-safety-and-security">The Dark Side of Digital License Plates: A Threat to Road Safety and Security&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The rise of digital license plates has been touted as a revolutionary step forward in the world of transportation. With the ability to update registration information, display personalized messages, and even track vehicle location, these high-tech plates seem like a convenient and efficient solution for drivers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, a recent exposé by Wired magazine has shed light on a disturbing vulnerability that could turn these digital marvels into tools of chaos.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Dark Side of AI: How the Industry Insatiable Appetite for Energy is Fueling a Climate Crisis</title><link>https://weeklyarxiv.github.io/posts/2024/12/ais-emissions-are-about-to-skyrocket-even-further/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 18:01:26 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://weeklyarxiv.github.io/posts/2024/12/ais-emissions-are-about-to-skyrocket-even-further/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="the-alarming-rate-of-data-center-emissions">&lt;strong>The Alarming Rate of Data Center Emissions&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The rapid growth of artificial intelligence (AI) has been hailed as a revolutionary force, transforming industries and revolutionizing the way we live and work. However, beneath the surface of this technological boom lies a disturbing reality: the AI industry&amp;rsquo;s insatiable appetite for energy is fueling a climate crisis.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A recent study by researchers at the Harvard T.H. Chan School of Public Health has shed light on the alarming rate at which data center emissions are skyrocketing, and the implications are dire.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>